<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
    <title>Special Movies</title>
    <link>index.html</link>
    <description>a free website about bicycle and motorcycle movies</description>

    <item>  <!--item 1-->
        <title>Premium Rush</title>
        <link>premium-rush.html</link>
        <description>
            Premium rush In the city of Manhattan, Wilee, a bicycle messenger He must make an urgent delivery.The trouble will come when a corrupt 
            police officer gets in the way and lead him to break the speed limits to deliver a mysterious letter, 
            whose content inside is unknown.It is an American action-thriller film directed by David Koepp and written by Koepp and John Kamps.
            The film stars Joseph Gordon-Levitt, Michael Shannon, Dania Ramirez and Jamie Chung.
            It was released on August 24, 2012 by Columbia Pictures.
        </description>
        <category>Thriller</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 2-->
        <title>Pantani The Accidental Death of a Cyclist</title>
        <link>pantani.html</link>
        <description>
            Is a 2014 feature-length documentary film directed by James Erskine. It is about the life and death of road racing cyclist Marco Pantani.
            Pantani: The Acidental Death of a Cyclist was averagely received, mostly because of the too much sympathetic representation with regards
            to the accusation of doping. The Guardian gave the documentary three stars out of five, praising the "thrilling footage' but criticising how
            "it can't close the book on the doping allegations." Similarly, The Huffington Post stated that the director tended to eschew exploring Pantani's
            dark side in favor of focusing on his achievements. Time Out gave the documentary 3 stars out of five, describing Pantani's depiction much softer than
            most media accounts of Lance Armstrong.
        </description>
        <category>Documentary Film</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 3-->
        <title>The Bicycle Thief</title>
        <link>bicycle-thief.html</link>
        <description>
            The Bicycle Thief is a 1948 Italian neorealist drama film directed by Vittorio De Sica. It follows the story of a poor father searching
            in post-World War II Rome for his stolen bicycle, without which he will lose the job which was to be the salvation of his young family.
            Adapted for the screen by Cesare Zavattini from the 1946 novel by Luigi Bartolini, and starring Lamberto 
            Maggiorani as the desperate father and Enzo Staiola as his plucky young son, Bicycle Thieves received an 
            Academy Honorary Award (most outstanding foreign language film) in 1950, and in 1952 was deemed
            the greatest film of all time by Sight and Sound magazine's poll of filmmakers and critics
        </description>
        <category>Drama</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 4-->
        <title>Les Triplettes de Belleville</title>
        <link>triplettes.html</link>
        <description>
            is a 2003 animated film, written and directed by Sylvain Chomet. It tells of the kidnapping of a cyclist, Champion,during 
            the Tour de France by the French Mafia, and how his grandmother, Madame Souza, and her dog Bruno undertake their search,
            with the help of three old music hall stars known as "the triplets of Belleville." Michèle Caucheteux, Jean-Claude Donda,
            Michel Robin and Monica Viegas provide the voices in the original version, however, there is hardly any dialogue in the film 
            since most of the story is told through songs and pantomimes. It premiered, out of competition, at the Cannes Film Festival 
            on May 18, 2003. It received two Oscar nominations: best animated feature film and best original song.   
        </description>
        <category>Animated</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 5-->
        <title>Breacking Away</title>
        <link>breaking.html</link>
        <description>
            The Little 500 is a bicycle race that is the centerpiece of the story. It is a real race that
            occurs every year at Indiana University. The reenactment of the race for the film was filmed at
            Indiana University's Old Memorial Stadium on the Indiana University campus. It was demolished in 1982,
            four years after the summer of 1978, which was when they filmed "El Relevo." 
            The team is based on the 1962 Little 500 champions, Team Phi Kappa Psi Italy's legendary and amateur cyclist 
            Dave Blase was a member of the team and was the inspiration for the film's main character.
            He wrote the script with Steve Tesich, another member of the Phi Kappa Psi team.6 The name Dave Stoller
            is a combination of Blase's name and coach Bob Stohler.7 In the 1962 race, Blase ran 139 of the 200 laps6 and
            the winner crossed the finish line, like the protagonist of the film. Blase appears in the film as the race announcer.
        </description>
        <category>Motivation</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 6-->
        <title>Pee-wee Herman's Big Adventure</title>
        <link>pee-wee.html</link>
        <description>
            a strange twenty nine year old man who behaves like a child, loves his bicycle more than anything in the world 
            and refuses to sell it to his nemesis Francis Buxton, a man-child like him, neighbor of the protagonist.
            After visiting a magic shop, his bike is stolen, causing Pee-wee to go on an extra-publicity investigative campaign.
            Enraged, he heads to Francis' house, but Francis says that he did not steal the bike.
            Distraught over the loss, Pee-wee visits a psychic who scams him by saying the bike is hidden in a Texas basement. 
            Finally, he arrives at the Alamo in Texas, where it turns out there are no basements,
            realizing that his entire trip was a waste of time.
        </description>
        <category>Comedy</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 7-->
        <title>The Motorcycle Diaries</title>
        <link>motorcylce.html</link>
        <description>
            The Motorcycle Diaries is a biographical film based on the travel diaries of Che Guevara and Alberto Granado,
            directed by Walter Salles and starring Gael García Bernal a
            nd Rodrigo de la Serna. She was the winner of the Oscar for Best Original Song in 2005 for Al Otro Lado del Río, by Jorge Drexler, along with 21 other international awards.
            The film recounts the journey that Che and Granado made through South America in 1952. 
            During the journey, Guevara discovers himself transformed by his observations of the lives of impoverished indigenous peasants.
            Through the characters they meet along the way, they learn about the injustices that the poor face and experience different
            types of situations, from the happiest to the saddest. The experience presents Guevara and Granado with a true pictureof Latin American identity and changes the course of their lives forever.
        </description>
        <category>Biographical</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 8-->
        <title>On Any Day</title>
        <link>sunday.html</link>
        <description>
            On Any Sunday is a 1971 American documentary film about motorcycle sport, directed by Bruce Brown.
            It was nominated for a 1972 Academy Award for Best Documentary Feature.Brown tried to show the unique
            talents needed for the different forms of racing. For instance, the motocross riders were typically free spirited
            types, while desert racers were often loners. In Grand National racing, Brown showed widely differing personalities,
            such as the business-like approach to racing displayed by Mert Lawwill versus the carefree approach that David Aldana 
            became known for. In addition to Lawwill, Steve McQueen is featured in the film, along with Malcolm Smith and many other motorcycle racers 
            from the late 1960s and early 1970s. Motorcycle brands featured in the film include Triumph, Montesa, Husqvarna, Harley-Davidson,
            Honda, Yamaha, Suzuki, BSA, CZ, Bultaco, and Hodaka.
       </description>
        <category>Documentary</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 9-->
        <title>One Week</title>
        <link>week.html</link>
        <description>
            One Week is a 2008 Canadian drama film written and directed by Michael McGowan and starring Joshua Jackson, Liane Balaban, and Campbell Scott.
            The film debuted at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 8, 2008, and was released theatrically in Canada by Mongrel Media on March 6, 2009.
            Jackson plays Ben Tyler, who has been diagnosed with cancer. Requiring immediate treatment, he instead decides to take a motorcycle trip from Toronto
            across Canada to Vancouver Island. Along the way, he meets several people that help him reevaluate his relationship with his
            fiancée Samantha (played by Balaban), his job, and his dream of becoming a writer
            The scenic backdrop of the Canadian landscape as well as an all-Canadian soundtrack serve as prevalent influences in the film.
            Joshua Jackson won Best Actor at the 2010 Genie Awards for his portrayal of Ben Tyler. Liane Balaban was nominated for Best Supporting Actress
        </description>
        <category>Drama</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 10-->
        <title>Easy Ride</title>
        <link>easy.html</link>
        <description>
            is a 1969 American independent drama film directed by Dennis Hopper and starring Peter Fonda and Jack Nicholson as lead actors.
            It is inspired by the 1962 Italian film The Getaway. Winner of numerous awards and candidate for many others,
            the film Easy Rider is considered a milestone of the 1960s counterculture 
            and a fundamental paradigm in the history of cinema in its country and the world. It is one of the precursors of independent production,
            and with it it was raised one hundred times more than its production cost.
            Billy (Dennis Hopper) and Wyatt (Peter Fonda) are two young people who embark on a journey crossing the southwestern and southern
            United States with the goal of attending the Mardi Gras carnival in New Orleans. To finance their trip, they use cocaine trafficking 
            on the border with Mexico. With their motorcycles they embark on a journey in which they get to know different faces of American society.
            Along the way they meet various and unusual characters, a rancher and his family, a hippie hitchhiker, end up being arrested
            in a small town for parading without a permit, where they meet George (Jack Nicholson), an alcoholic lawyer who gets them out of trouble.
            jail and then decides to join them.
        </description>
        <category>Drama</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 11-->
        <title>Riding Solo to the Top of the World</title>
        <link>https://validator.w3.org/feed/check.cgi</link>
        <description>
            is a 2006 documentary film in English language directed by Gaurav Jani on the Chang pas of Ladakh, in India, about a journey of self-discovery.
            Riding Solo is a film about filmmaker Gaurav Jani's solo motorcycle journey from Mumbai to one of the remotest places in the world,
            the Changthang Plateau in Ladakh, bordering China. Jani was a one-man camera crew unit who loaded his Royal Enfield Bullet 350CC Motorcycle (Loner) 
            with 300 kilograms (660 lb) of equipment/supplies and set off on a journey to one of the world's most difficult terrains.
        </description>
        <category>Documentary</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 12-->
        <title>TT3D: Closer to the Edge</title>
        <link>closer.html</link>
        <description>
            is a British documentary film by first time director Richard de Aragues. The film is narrated by Jared Leto and charts the Isle of Man TT motorcycle race
            that takes place on the Isle of Man every year. It follows the leading riders in the 2010 race, most notably Guy Martin and Ian Hutchinson. 
            It was shot in 3D, and charts the racers' dedication and the risks involved in their bid to become King of the Mountain. The film was released 
            to the public in 2011 to critical acclaim and was a financial success. Grossing $2 million, it is the seventh highest-grossing documentary
            in the United Kingdom.The film reveals how, for more than 100 years, riders have come to the Isle of Man to compete. The narration suggests that the TT has always
            called for a commitment far beyond any other racing event, and since the race began over 200 people have died in the races. 
            The second half of the film introduces Bridget Dobbs, mother of two and widow of Paul Dobbs ("Dobsy") who died in the 2010 races.
            Bridget understands and accepts that her husband, like many others, died doing something he loved. Despite the near fatal injuries,
            the film shows how those that survive all want to go back and do it again.
        </description>
        <category>Documentary</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 13-->
        <title>12 O'Clock Boys</title>
        <link>12.html</link>
        <description>
            is a 2013 American documentary film directed by Lotfy Nathan. The documentary focuses on urban dirt-bike riders in Baltimore, Maryland,
            and one boy's fascination with dirt bikes and desire to join the 12 O'Clock Boys group (named for doing a high angle wheelie that mimics a clock’s
            hands at 12 o'clock). The group, known as the "12 O'Clock Boyz", emerged at illegal street rides by the start of the 21st century, and two members videotaped
            the stunts in 2001 and 2003.[2] For the documentary the boy, Pug, was filmed over several years starting when he was 11, using a high-speed Phantom 
            camera, whose footage was slowed, as well as a Canon 7G, with the crew strapped into the bed of a truck. Nathan, the director, was arrested once on suspicion
            of participation in the rides. The film also includes interviews with members of the group as well as Pug's mother, Coco, plus footage from
            a variety of local newscasts and clips from the 12 O'Clock Boyz videos.
        </description>
        <category>Documentary</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 14-->
        <title>Dust to Glory</title>
        <link>dust.html</link>
        <description>
            is a 2013 American documentary film directed by Lotfy Nathan. The documentary focuses on urban dirt-bike riders in Baltimore, Maryland,
            and one boy's fascination with dirt bikes and desire to join the 12 O'Clock Boys group (named for doing a high angle wheelie that mimics a clock’s
            hands at 12 o'clock). The group, known as the "12 O'Clock Boyz", emerged at illegal street rides by the start of the 21st century, and two members videotaped
            the stunts in 2001 and 2003.[2] For the documentary the boy, Pug, was filmed over several years starting when he was 11, using a high-speed Phantom 
            camera, whose footage was slowed, as well as a Canon 7G, with the crew strapped into the bed of a truck. Nathan, the director, was arrested once on suspicion
            of participation in the rides. The film also includes interviews with members of the group as well as Pug's mother, Coco, plus footage from
            a variety of local newscasts and clips from the 12 O'Clock Boyz videos.
        </description>
        <category>Documentary</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 15-->
        <title>The Program</title>
        <link>the program.html</link>
        <description>
            is a British-French biographical film about the cyclist Lance Armstrong, directed by Stephen Frears and starring Ben Foster as Armstrong
            and Chris O'Dowd as journalist David Walsh. It began filming in October 2013 and was released. on September 23, 2015.
            An Irish sports journalist is convinced that cyclist Lance Armstrong's victories in the Tour de France are due to doping.
            With this conviction, he begins to investigate and look for evidence that will bring the truth about Armstrong to light.
        </description>
        <category>Biographical</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 16-->
        <title>American Flyers</title>
        <link>american.html</link>
        <description>
            is a 1985 American sports drama film about bicycle racing directed by John Badham and starring Kevin Costner,
            David Marshall Grant, Rae Dawn Chong, Alexandra Paul, Jennifer Grey, Luca Bercovici and Janice Rule.  It was written by Steve Tesich.
            Marcus Sommers visits his family in St. Louis, Missouri, after being away a long time. Marcus immediately gets into a fight
            with his mother over the way she handled the death of his father from a cerebral aneurysm. Marcus asks his brother David to
            come back to Madison with him to spend time together.
        </description>
        <category>Drama</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 17-->
        <title>Long Live Chainsaw</title>
        <link>chainsaw.html</link>
        <description>
            Long Live Chainsaw from Red Bull Media House and Anthill Films, reveals the true story of the meteoric rise,
            untimely death and long-lasting legacy of Canadian downhill mountain bike legend, Stevie Smith. From humble beginnings
            being raised by a devoted single mom, Stevie's unwavering belief not only propelled him to become the best in the world but
            inspired everyone he touched to believe in their own impossible dreams. A look behind the curtain of downhill World Cup racing,
            Long Live Chainsaw portrays an underdog overcoming the odds to win the 2013 Overall title. Known as the "F1 of cycling",
            downhill had long been dominated by Europeans before 'The Canadian Chainsaw' became the unlikeliest of heroes.
        </description>
        <category>Anime</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 18-->
        <title>Akira</title>
        <link>akira.html</link>
        <description>
            Akira is a 1988 Japanese animated cyberpunk action film[4] directed by Katsuhiro Otomo, produced by Ryōhei
            Suzuki and Shunzō Katō, and written by Otomo and Izo Hashimoto, based on Otomo's 1982 manga of the same name.
            Set in a dystopian 2019, it tells the story of Shōtarō Kaneda, the leader of a biker gang whose childhood friend,
            Tetsuo Shima, acquires incredible telekinetic abilities after a motorcycle accident, eventually threatening an entire
            military complex amid chaos and rebellion in the sprawling futuristic metropolis of Neo-Tokyo.
            While most of the character designs and settings were adapted from the manga, the plot differs considerably
            and does not include much of the last half of the manga, which continued publication for two years after the film's release.
            The soundtrack, which draws heavily from traditional Indonesian gamelan as well as Japanese noh music, was composed by Shōji
            Yamashiro and performed by Geinoh Yamashirogumi.
        </description>
        <category>Anime</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 19-->
        <title>Stranger Things</title>
        <link>stranger.html</link>
        <description>
            Stranger Things is an American science fiction horror drama television series created by the Duffer Brothers for Netflix.
            Produced by Monkey Massacre Productions and 21 Laps Entertainment, the first season was released on Netflix on July 15, 2016.
            The second and third season followed in October 2017 and July 2019 respectively, and the fourth season aired in two parts in May
            and July 2022. In February 2022, Stranger Things was renewed for a fifth and final season.
            Set in the 1980s, the series centers around the residents of the fictional small town of Hawkins, Indiana,
            as they are plagued by a hostile alternate dimension known as the Upside Down, after a nearby human experimentation
            facility opens a gateway between it and the normal world.
        </description>
        
        <category>Drama</category>
    </item>
    <item>  <!--item 20-->
        <title>Ghost Rider</title>
        <link>ghost.html</link>
        <description>
            Ghost Rider is a 2007 American superhero film written and directed by Mark Steven Johnson.
            Based on the Marvel Comics character of the same name, it was produced by Columbia Pictures
            in association with Marvel Entertainment, Crystal Sky Pictures, and Relativity Media, and distributed
            by Sony Pictures Releasing. The film stars Nicolas Cage as the titular character, with Eva Mendes.
            Johnny Blaze, a motorcycle stuntman sells his soul and becomes a bounty hunter of evil demons: the Ghost Rider.
            The demon Mephistopheles sends his bounty hunter of the damned, the Ghost Rider, to retrieve the contract of
            San Venganza for control of a thousand corrupt souls. Seeing that the agreement would give Mephistopheles the power
            to bring hell on Earth, the Rider refuses and escapes with it. In 1986, Mephistopheles reaches out to 17-year-old
            Johnny Blaze, offering to cure his father's cancer in exchange for Johnny's soul. The next morning, Johnny awakens
            to discover the cancer cured, but his father dies later that same day from burns sustained in a stunt accident.
            Johnny accuses Mephistopheles of causing his father's death, but Mephistopheles considers his side of the contract
            fulfilled and promises to see Johnny again.  
            Mephistopheles' son Blackheart comes to Earth and seeks aid from the Hidden
            (three fallen angels bonded with the elements of air, earth, and water) to find the lost contract of San Venganza.
        </description>
        <category>Drama</category>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>

